Finding Aid for Oncology Nursing Society, Ann Arbor Chapter Records, 1980-2004
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Oncology Nursing Society, Ann Arbor Chapter records 1980-2004
Oncology Nursing Society. Ann Arbor Chapter.
03129 Bf 2
Local chapter formed in 1977 and chartered in 1981, part of a national organization of registered nurses and hematology and oncology health care professionals. Focus is on transforming care of cancer patients. Chapter information including newsletters, annual reports and records of organization's officers detailing meetings, policies, educational programs, and events. Some unidentified photographs are also included.
1.5 linear feet
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The record group (Donor 9207 ) was received in 2002. An additional accession was received in 2004.
The record group is open to research.
The Ann Arbor local chapter of the Oncology Nursing Society (ONS) was formed in 1977 and received its charter from the national organization in 1981. Part of a national organization of more than 30,000 registered nurses and hematology/oncology health care professionals, the Ann Arbor chapter aims to transform the care of cancer patients by increasing excellence in teaching, research and education in oncology. To accommodate these goals the Ann Arbor chapter organizes lectures and other events focusing on awareness and education; publishes a newsletter; hosts an annual banquet and conducts fundraising activities; regularly contacts governmental representatives regarding health care policy and reform; and participates in the annual ONS Congress. These activities link the chapter's local efforts to the largest professional membership oncology association in the world.
An annually elected board governs the chapter and its activities are managed through six committees. Officers in the board include President, Secretary, Treasurer and President Elect. The membership committee promotes recruitment and retention of members. The nominations committee recruits members to run for chapter office. The program committee coordinates educational programs and plans events. The fundraising committee generates funds for the local chapter by seeking out corporate sponsorships and by planning events. The newsletter committee writes and assembles Oncolog, the chapter newsletter. The government relations committee coordinates letter-writing campaigns and chapter responses to immediate concerns in health care policy and reform.
The records of the Ann Arbor Chapter of the Oncology Nursing Society consist of Chapter information including newsletters, annual reports and records of organization's officers detailing meetings, policies, educational programs, and events. Some unidentified photographs are also included. the records are organized into two series: General and Officer Records and Committee Records.
Subjects:
Oncology Nursing Society. Ann Arbor Chapter.; Cancer--Nursing.; Nursing--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Nurses--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Photographs.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.
- General and Officer Records
  The General and Officer Records series includes some general chapter information such as bound chapter policy manuals or the application for recognition from the national organization, as well as records attributed to particular officers of the elected board. These records were arranged in chronological order whenever possible, although care was taken to stay as close to the original order of the records as possible. Programs, Minutes, Correspondence and Membership documents for example, were originally filed together in binders kept by the chapter's first secretaries, although later secretaries chose to arrange these files in different ways. The Secretary subseries is the most extensive of all the subseries in this collection and the researcher is advised to look within this section for records not found elsewhere, as the secretary often collected and accounted for the records of other officers and committee members.
  - General
    - National Chapter Department of Archives and Records (Box 1)
    - Local Chapter Application, Bound Charter Copy 1980 (Box 1)
    - Oncology Nursing Society, Bound Chapter Policy Manual 1993 (Box 1)
    - By-laws (Box 1)
    - Recognition (Box 1)
    - Photographs (Box 1)
    - History 1982-1984 (Box 1)
  - President
    - Annual Report 1989 (Box 1)
    - Annual Reports 1997-2001 (Box 1)
    - Charter Renewal Documents 1989-1999 (Box 1)
    - Letters to Donors 1995 (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous Documentation 2001 (Box 1)
  - Treasurer
    - Commercial Liability and Tax Information 1986-1996 (Box 1)
    - Annual Report 1988 (Box 1)
    - Charter Renewal and Treasurer's Report 1989-1995 (Box 1)
    - Reports 1996-1999 (Box 1)
  - Secretary
    - Programs, Minutes, Correspondence and Membership 1982-1983 (Box 1)
    - Programs, Minutes, Correspondence and Membership 1983-1984 (Box 1)
    - Programs, Minutes, Correspondence and Membership 1984-1985 (Box 1)
    - Programs, Minutes, Correspondence and Membership 1985-1986 (Box 1)
    - Programs, Minutes and Correspondence 1986-1987 (Box 1)
    - Programs and Correspondence 1986-1987 (Box 1)
    - Programs and Correspondence 1987-1988 (Box 1)
    - Committee and Board Membership 1988-1990 (Box 1)
    - Correspondence 1988-1990 (Box 1)
    - Board Meeting Minutes 1988-1990 (Box 1)
    - Membership Survey 1988-1990 (Box 1)
    - Standing Rules 1988-1990 (Box 1)
    - Strategic Plans 1988-1997 (Box 1)
    - Membership Surveys and Results 1989-1992 (Box 1)
    - Committee and Board Membership 1990-1992 (Box 1)
    - Programs and Correspondence 1990-1992 (Box 1)
    - Board Meeting Minutes 1990-1992 (Box 1)
    - Mentorship Retreats 1990-1992 (Box 1)
    - Chapter Policy Manual 1990-1992 (Box 1)
    - Strategic Plans 1990-1992 (Box 1)
    - Chapter and Committee Membership 1991-1995 (Box 1)
    - Programs and Correspondence 1992-1994 (Box 1)
    - Board Meeting Minutes 1992-1994 (Box 1)
    - National information and Standing Rules 1992-1994 (Box 1)
    - Board, Committee and Chapter Membership 1994-1995 (Box 1)
    - Correspondence 1994-1995 (Box 1)
    - Board Meeting Minutes 1994-1995 (Box 1)
    - Membership Survey 1994-1995 (Box 1)
    - Board Meeting Minutes 1997-2001 (Box 2)
- Committee Records
  The Committee Records series, although not as consistently documented as the Secretary subseries, still provides the researcher with a great deal of information. The flyers of scheduled programs, chapter newsletters, letters to legislators, and the minutes of committee meetings may prove to be particularly useful.
  - Community Outreach (Box 2)
  - Membership Committee
    - Correspondence and Brochures 1989-1994 (Box 2)
    - Membership Meeting Minutes 1988-1992 (Box 2)
    - General (Box 2)
  - Nominating Committee
    - General Information and Correspondence 1989-1996 (Box 2)
    - Survey Response 1993 (Box 2)
    - Awards Correspondence and Applications 1995 (Box 2)
    - Roberta Schofield Award 1988-1995 (Box 2)
    - Ballots (Box 2)
    - Election Reporting (Box 2)
    - Strategic Planning (Box 2)
  - Programming Committee
    - Programs and Flyers 1986-1987 (Box 2)
    - Programs and Flyers 1988-1990 (Box 2)
    - Programs and Flyers 1991-1993 (Box 2)
    - Programs and Flyers 1994-1995 (Box 2)
    - Correspondence and Minutes 1988-1992 (Box 2)
    - Spring Banquet 1990 (Box 2)
    - Events 2003-2004 (Box 2)
    - Filling in the Gaps (Box 2)
  - Fundraising Committee
    - Correspondence and Minutes 1988-1994 (Box 2)
  - Newsletter Committee
    - Oncolog, Ann Arbor Chapter newsletter, 1987-1995, 1998-2001 (Box 2)
    - Correspondence and Mission 1989-1990 (Box 2)
  - Government Relations Committee
    - Letters to Legislators 1991 (Box 2)
    - Objectives, Minutes and Strategic Plan 1992 (Box 2)
    - Minutes and Memoranda 1993 (Box 2)
Related Material
The researcher should be aware that the Oncology Nursing Society has a strong national archive program presided over by a professional archivist. Documentation describing the organization's national archives can be found in the first folder of the chapter records housed at the Bentley Library. The policy manual in the records also features extensive record keeping guidelines for local chapters, which may be of interest to researchers as well. The researcher is also advised to look at the national website for further information. As of 2002, this can be found at: http://www.ons.org/.